Register of the Freda Utley Papers, 1886-1978
Hoover Institution Archives
- Correspondence, Chronological, 1919-1976
  - 1943 (Folder 14)
  - 1944 (Folder 15)
  - 1945 (Folder 16)
  - 1946 (Folder 17)
  - 1947 (Folder 18)
  - 1948 (Folder 19)
  - 1949 (Box 15., Folder l)
  - 1950 (Folder 2)
  - 1951 (Folder 3)
  - 1952 (Folder 4)
  - 1953 (Box 16., Folder 1)
  - 1954 (Folder 2)
  - 1955 (Folder 3)
  - 1956 (Folder 4)
  - 1957 (Folder 5)
  - 1958 (Box 17., Folder 1)
  - 1959 (Folder 2)
  - 1960 (Folder 3)
  - 1961 (Folder 4)
  - 1962 (Folder 5)
  - 1963 (Folder 6)
  - 1964 (Folder 7)
  - 1965 (Folder 8)
  - 1966 (Folder 9)
  - 1967 (Folder 10)
  - 1968 (Folder 11)
  - 1969 (Folder 12)
  - 1970 (Folder 13)
  - 1971 (Folder 14)
  - 1972 (Folder 15)
  - 1973 (Folder 16)
  - 1974 (Folder 17)
  - 1975 (Folder 18)
  - 1976 (Folder 19)
  - Undated (includes many fragments of letters) (Box 18., Folder 1-3)
- Speeches And Writings, Dated, 1930-1974
  - "Safeguarding the Geisha," New Statesman and Nation, Sept. 13, 1930 (Box 18., Folder 4)
  - Japan's Feet of Clay, 1936 (reviews and financial statements) (Folder 5)
  - Japan Can Be Stopped (pamphlet co-authored with David Wills), 1937 (reviews) (Folder 6)
  - "A Chinese Popular Front?" New Statesman and Nation, Jan. 9, 1937 (Folder 7)
  - "Why Labour Is Cheap in Japan," Manchester Evening News, Jan. 18, 1937 (Folder 8)
  - "Humours of Trading in China," New Statesman and Nation, Apr. 3, 1937 (review of Carl Crow, 400 Million Customers) (Folder 9)
  - "Why Japan Makes War Now," News Chronicle (London), July 28, 1937 (Folder 10)
  - "What Does Japan Want? Background of the War in the East," Common Sense, Sept. 1937 (Folder 11)
  - "Why Japan May Meet Her Waterloo," Reynolds News, Sept. 19, 1937 (Folder 12)
  - "Japan Fears a Boycott," Nation, Oct. 2, 1937 (Folder 13)
  - "Why China Must Not Be Conquered," News Chronicle (London), Oct. 5, 1937 (Folder 14)
  - "Comment On Pourrait Arr^ter l'Agression Japonaise: Ses Faiblesses Economiques et Sociales," Journal des Nations, Oct. 6, 1937 (Folder 15)
  - "Dossier des Agressions Totalitaires: On Peut Encore Enrayer l'Agression Japonaise," Journal des Nations, Nov. 25, 1937 (Folder 16)
  - "The Vulnerability of Japan," New Statesman and Nation, Dec. 25, 1937 (letter to the editor) (Folder 17)
  - Japan's Gamble in China, 1938 (reviews) (Box 19., Folder 1)
  - "The Japanese God," New Statesman and Nation, Jan. 22, 1938 (review of Carl Crow, I Speak for the Chinese) (Folder 2)
  - "Japan Now Feels the Boycott," News Chronicle (London), May 16, 1938 (Folder 3)
  - "The Danube and the Yellow River," New Statesman and Nation, June 11, 1938 (Folder 4)
  - "Japanese Prepare Big Drive," News Chronicle (London), July 19, 1938 (Folder 5)
  - "More Civilians Massacred by Japan's Planes," News Chronicle (London), July 20, 1938 (Folder 6)
  - "Truckloads of Babies Escape Bombs," News Chronicle (London), July 22, 1938 (Folder 7)
  - "China Will Fight On and Defend Hankow," News Chronicle (London), Aug. 4, 1938 (Folder 8)
  - "A Day in Canton," New Statesman and Nation, Aug. 13, 1938 (Folder 9)
  - "The South Yangtze Front," New Statesman and Nation, Oct. 15, 1938 (Folder 10)
  - "A Woman in China's War Zone," San Francisco Chronicle, Nov. 27, 1938 (Folder 11)
  - China at War, 1939 (reviews and financial statements) (Folder 12)
  - "Having It Both Ways," Far Eastern Service, 1939 (Folder 13)
  - "The Knouto-Soviet State," Observer (London), 1939 (review of Boris Souvarine, Stalin: A Critical Survey of Bolshevism) (Folder 14)
  - "War Aims," New Statesman and Nation, 1939 (letter to the editor) (Folder 15)
  - "An Iron Constitution!" Synopsis, Jan. 1939 (Folder 16)
  - "China," New Statesman and Nation, Jan. 28, 1939 (letter to the editor) (Folder 17)
  - "China's Many Problems: Left or Right? Wang Ching-wei's Departure: A New Stage Beginning," Manchester Guardian, Feb. 2, 1939 (Folder 18)
  - "Japan Beginning to Feel the Pinch," Far Eastern Service, June 7, 1939 (Folder 19)
  - "Incidents and the Currency War in North China," Far Eastern Service, June 14, 1939 (Folder 20)
  - "The Blockade of Tientsin: Japan's Aims: Currency Control in North China: Need of Foreign Exchange," Manchester Guardian, June 19, 1939 (Folder 21)
  - "Tientsin: The Choice Before Us," Far Eastern Service, June 21, 1939 (Folder 22)
  - "Tientsin," New Statesman and Nation, June 24, 1939 (Folder 23)
  - "Tientsin," Far Eastern Service, June 26, 1939 (Folder 24)
  - "Currency Control in North China: 'Background' of Tientsin Blockade: Worthless Japanese Paper," Johannesburg Star, July 1, 1939 (Folder 25)
  - "Who's Who in Asia," New Statesman and Nation, July 1, 1939 (review of John Gunther, Inside Asia) (Folder 26)
  - "Can We Stay in China?" News Chronicle (London), July 5, 1939 (Folder 27)
  - "Second Anniversary of the Sino-Japanese War," New Statesman and Nation, July 8, 1939 (Folder 28)
  - "Front Line Horrors," Daily Record (Glasgow), July 10, 1939 (Folder 29)
  - "China at War," North Mail and Newcastle Chronicle, July 11, 1939 (Folder 30)
  - "Upper and Middle Class Idlers," Manchester Daily Dispatch, July 12, 1939 (Folder 31)
  - "The Sino-Japanese War," July 14, 1939 (radio interview with W. H. Stoneman) (Folder 32)
  - "Will a Betrayal of China Profit Us?" Far Eastern Service, July 27, 1939 (Folder 33)
  - "Serve Notice on Japan!" Daily Herald (Manchester), Aug. 7, 1939 (Folder 34)
  - "The Tokyo Negotiations," Service Extr`me-Orient, Aug.9, 1939 (Folder 35)
  - "Co-operate with America - or Japan?" Time and Tide, Aug. 12, 1939 (Folder 36)
  - "Habeas Corpus in the Far East?" Far Eastern Service, Aug. 16, 1939 (Folder 37)
  - "The Chinese Currency Problem," Far Eastern Service, Aug. 23, 1939 (Folder 38)
  - "Left in the Lurch," Sept. 1, 1939 (Folder 39)
  - Letter to the editor, New Statesman and Nation, Sept. 30, 1939 (Folder 40)
  - "China and Japan: Two Views of the Struggle," Observer (London), Oct. 15, 1939 (review of C. R. Shepherd, The Case against Japan, and I. Epstein, The People's War) (Folder 41)
  - "Has Stalin Become a 'Trotskyist'?" Common Sense, Dec. 1939 (Folder 42)
  - The Dream We Lost, 1940
    - Drafts (Folder 43)
    - Promotional material (Folder 44)
    - Reviews (Folder 45)
  - "Making the World Safe for Stalin," 1940 (Box 20., Folder 1)
  - "Who Owns the Future?" 1940? (Folder 2)
  - "Today and the Far East," Independent Woman, Mar. 1940 (Folder 3)
  - "Japan and the Double Standard," Common Sense, May 1940 (Folder 4)
  - "Russia and Germany," July 1, 1940 (radio address) (Folder 5)
  - "Japan's Great Bluff," Nation, Oct. 12, 1940 (Folder 6)
  - "The Limits of Russian Resistance," 1941 (Folder 7)
  - "The Russo-German War," 1941 (Folder 8)
  - "What Shall It Profit a Man..., or, The Great Delusion," 1941 (Folder 9)
  - "Will Russia Betray China?" 1941 (Folder 10)
  - "Revolutions and Reality," Saturday Review of Literature, Jan. 18, 1941 (review of Jan Valtin, Out of the Night) (Folder 11)
  - "A Terse, Authentic Report of the Terror in China," New York Times Book Review, Mar. 9, 1941 (review of Edgar Snow, The Battle for Asia) (Folder 12)
  - "Can Democracy Survive Total War?" Apr. 4, 1941 (address, annual meeting of the American Academy of Political and Social Science, Philadelphia; published in Annals of the American Academy of Political and Social Science, July 1941) (Folder 13)
  - "If You Could See What I Have Seen," Asia, July 1941 (clippings about article only) (Folder 14)
  - "Must the World Destroy Itself?" Common Sense, Aug. 1941 (reprinted in Reader's Digest, Oct. 1941; includes clippings about article) (Folder 15)
  - Speech, Oct. 15, 1941? (Folder 16)
  - "How Could We Combat a Hitler-Dominated Europe?" Nov. 16, 1941 (American Forum of the Air radio symposium with John M. Vorys, H. R. Knickerbocker and Herbert Elliston) (Folder 17)
  - "This War Can and Will be Won: Jap Treachery Unites All U.S.," New York Journal-American, Dec. 14, 1941 (Folder 18)
  - "Japan Is Not Germany," 1942 (Folder 19)
  - Letter to the editor, New York Herald-Tribune, Oct. 1942 (Folder 20)
  - Letter to the editor, New York Herald-Tribune, Nov. 24, 1942 (date written) (Folder 21)
  - "Britain at the Halfway House," Asia, 1943 (Folder 22)
  - "The Totalitarian Menace Within," 1943 (Folder 23)
  - "Big Business and Communists: A New Alliance," New Leader, May 22, 1943 (Folder 24)
  - Review of Harry Paxton Howard, America's Role in Asia, Shanghai Evening Post and Mercury, July 23, 1943 (Folder 25)
  - "Stalin's Recognition of the Badoglio Regime," New Leader, Mar. 18, 1944 (Folder 26)
  - "A British Plea for India's Freedom," Progressive, Apr. 24, 1944 (review of H. N. Brailsford, Subject India) (Folder 27)
  - "British Realism," Progressive, May 22, 1944 (Folder 28)
  - "The Theory of Realism," New Leader, June 17, 1944 (review of Alfred Bingham, The Practice of Idealism) (Folder 29)
  - "Frances Gunther's Revolution in India," Progressive, July 3, 1944 (book review) (Folder 30)
  - "Why Pick on China?" American Mercury, Sept. 1944 (Folder 31)
  - "When, How, and If Russia Fights Japan," Progressive, Mar. 26, 1945 (Folder 32)
  - "Are They Real Communists?" Apr. 19, 1945 (Folder 33)
  - "To Have and to Hold," Shanghai Evening Post and Mercury, Nov. 10, 1945 (Folder 34)
  - "Inflation," Shanghai Evening Post and Mercury, Nov. 13, 1945 (Folder 35)
  - "Vengeance, Justice and Economic Rehabilitation," Shanghai Evening Post and Mercury, Nov. 16, 1945 (Folder 36)
  - "Manchuria," Shanghai Evening Post and Mercury, Nov. 19, 1945 (Folder 37)
  - "Prospects for Foreign Business in China," Shanghai Evening Post and Mercury, Nov. 21, 1945 (Folder 38)
  - "China's Responsibilities," Shanghai Evening Post and Mercury, Nov. 23, 1945 (Folder 39)
  - "China's New Supreme Economic Council," Shanghai Evening Post and Mercury, Nov. 30, 1945 (Folder 40)
  - "Views of China," Shanghai Evening Post and Mercury, Dec. 5, 1945 (Folder 41)
  - "Pearl Harbor," Shanghai Evening Post and Mercury, Dec. 11, 1945 (Folder 42)
  - "King Can Do No Wrong," Shanghai Evening Post and Mercury, Dec. 19, 1945 (Folder 43)
  - "Peace on Earth, Good Will towards Men," Shanghai Evening Post and Mercury, Dec. 24, 1945 (Folder 44)
  - "The Hour of Decision," China Critic, Dec. 27, 1945 (Folder 45)
  - "General Marshall's Failure in China, or, Time for a Change in China," 1946 (Folder 46)
  - "The Plain Facts of Yenan: A U.S. Journalist Finds the Chinese Communists Run True to Form," 1946 (Folder 47)
  - "Manchuria: The First Test and the Last," Foreign Notes, Apr. 12, 1946 (Box 21., Folder 1)
  - "See Red China in U.S. Policy: Soviet Domination Growing since Yalta Deal with Stalin," New York Journal-American, July 7, 1946 (Folder 2)
  - "Mme. Sun Yat-sen's Appeal," July 23, 1946 (co-signer with Alfred Kohlberg and others) (Folder 3)
  - Statement to Secretary of State James F. Byrnes, July 24, 1946 (co-signer with others) (Folder 4)
  - "What Should We Do about China?" Aug. 20, 1946 (American Forum of the Air radio symposium with Harrison Forman, J. Spencer Kennard and Alfred Kohlberg) (Folder 5)
  - "'Behind the Curtain,'" Washington Post, Sept. 7, 1946 (letter to the editor) (Folder 6)
  - Letter to the editor, New York Times, Sept. 12, 1946 (date written) (Folder 7)
  - "Communistic Activities, as Especially Related to the Far East," Dec. 18, 1946 (speech, Washington, D.C.) (Folder 8)
  - Last Chance in China, 1947
    - Drafts (Folder 9-12)
    - Promotional material (Box 22., Folder 1)
    - Reviews (Folder 2)
  - "Letters from Russia," 1947 (Folder 3)
  - Radio interview, Nov. 14, 1947 (Woman of Tomorrow program with Nancy Craig) (Folder 4)
  - Radio interview, Nov. 22, 1947 (with Irene Kuhn and Rene Kuhn) (Folder 5)
  - "America's Stake in China," Dec. 2, 1947 (Folder 6)
  - "America's Unrealistic View of China," 1948 (Folder 7)
  - Letter to the editor, Saturday Review of Literature, 1948 (Folder 8)
  - Lost Illusion, 1948 (revised version of The Dream We Lost)
    - Drafts (Folder 9)
    - Printed copy (Folder 10)
    - Promotional material (Folder 11)
    - Reviews (Folder 12)
  - "Sees U.S. Blunders Giving China to Reds: Expert Would End Appeasement," Mar. 7, 1948 (Folder 13)
  - "Our Futile China Policy," New York Journal-American, Mar. 8-9, 1948 (two-part article) (Folder 14)
  - "Marshall and Coalition Government: Our China Policy," New Leader, Mar. 27, 1948 (Folder 15)
  - "Decline and Fall," Human Events, Apr. 21, 1948 (Folder 16)
  - "Let's Face the Facts in China," Sign, May 1948 (Folder 17)
  - "Ruhr Wrecking Goes On: Arms Factory Stays: Siegen Loses Plants of Peace Time Use," Chicago Daily Tribune, Oct. 18, 1948 (Folder 18)
  - The High Cost of Vengeance, 1949
    - Drafts (Box 23., Folder 1-4)
    - Galleys (Folder 5)
    - Promotional material (Folder 6)
    - Reviews (Folder 7)
  - "Obstacle to German Recovery: Dismantling of Equipment Opposed as Loss to Europe's Economy," New York Times, Mar. 11, 1949 (letter to the editor) (Box 24., Folder 1)
  - "Author's View," New York Times, Aug. 7, 1949 (letter to the editor) (Folder 2)
  - Letter to the editor, New York Times, Oct. 10, 1949 (date written) (Folder 3)
  - "Bungled into War: From Yalta to Korea," Nov. 29, 1949 (synopsis of projected book) (Folder 4)
  - "According China Recognition: Criticizing Britain's Course, Author Warns against Similar Action by Us," New York Times, Dec. 8, 1949 (letter to the editor) (Folder 5)
  - "Sheean's Newest Pilgrimage," Plain Talk, Jan. 1950 (review of Vincent Sheean, Lead Kindly Light) (Folder 6)
  - "Course of United States Policy in China," Feb. 1950 (Folder 7)
  - "The Real Strength of Communism," Plain Talk, Mar. 1950 (review of A. Rossi, A Communist Party in Action) (Folder 8)
  - "Chasing Chameleons," Human Events, Mar. 29, 1950 (Folder 9)
  - Letter to the editor, Washington Post, Apr. 14, 1950 (date written) (Folder 10)
  - Testimony, U.S. Senate Foreign Relations Committee, May 1, 1950 (Folder 11)
  - Untitled, May 13, 1950 (Folder 12)
  - Review of Louis Francis Budenz, Men without Faces: The Communist Conspiracy in the U.S.A., Human Events, July 12, 1950 (Folder 13)
  - Review of Victor Serge, The Case of Comrade Tulayev, Human Events, Aug. 30, 1950 (Folder 14)
  - "What 'Second Crusade' Has Got Us Into," Chicago Sunday Tribune, Oct. 15, 1950 (review of William Henry Chamberlin, America's Second Crusade) (Folder 15)
  - "The Incurables," Freeman, Oct. 16, 1950 (review of Victor Serge, The Case of Comrade Tulayev) (Folder 16)
  - The China Story, 1951
    - Drafts (Folder 17)
    - Printed copy (Folder 18)
    - Promotional material (Folder 19)
    - Reviews (Folder 20)
  - Review of Barbara West, Policy for the West, Keith Hutchison, The Decline and Fall of British Capitalism, and Frederic R. Sanborn, Design for War: A Study of Secret Power Politics, 1937-1941, Economic Council Review of Books, Mar. 1951 (Box 25., Folder 1)
  - Review of B. H. Liddell Hart, Defence of the West, Elinor Lipper, Eleven Years in Soviet Prison Camps, Helen MacInnes, Neither Five nor Three, and Douglas Reed, Somewhere South of Suez, Economic Council Review of Books, Apr. 1951 (Folder 2)
  - Review of Sumner Welles, Seven Decisions that Shaped History, Women Investors Research Institute, Special Report No. 80l in re Will Present United Policies Defeat Communist World Empire Program? and Henry C. Link, The Way to Security, Economic Council Review of Books, May 1951 (Folder 3)
  - Review of Paul G. Hoffman, Peace Can Be Won, Leigh White, Balkan Caesar: Tito versus Stalin, and Hede Massing, This Deception, Economic Council Review of Books, June 1951 (Folder 4)
  - "The Case of Owen Lattimore," American Mercury, Sept. 1951 (Folder 5)
  - Review of Edward Crankshaw, Cracks in the Kremlin Wall, and Elizabeth Bentley, Out of Bondage, Economic Council Review of Books, Oct. 1951 (Folder 6)
  - Testimony, U.S. Senate Committee on the Judiciary Subcommittee to Investigate the Administration of the Internal Security Act and Other Internal Security Laws, Oct. 11, 1951 (Folder 7)
  - "And Now the Smear of the McCarran Committee," Human Events, Oct. 17, 1951 (Folder 8)
  - Review of William F. Buckley, Jr., God and Man at Yale, and George F. Kennan, American Diplomacy, 1900-1950, Economic Council Review of Books, Nov. 1951 (Folder 9)
  - Review of Robert A. Taft, A Foreign Policy for Americans, Joseph McCarthy, Retreat from Victory: The Story of George Catlett Marshall, and Gary MacEoin, The Communist War on Religion, Economic Council Review of Books, Jan. 1952 (Folder 10)
  - "How a Handful of Americans Gave East Asia to Russia," Pathfinder, Feb. 6, 1952 (Folder 11)
  - "Gen. Willoughby's Report on Sorge Spy Conspiracy," Chicago Sunday Tribune, Feb. 10, 1952 (review of Charles A. Willoughby, Shanghai Conspiracy: The Sorge Spy Ring) (Folder 12)
  - "Was It Treason or Ignorance that Destroyed Our Far East Policy?" Pathfinder, Feb. 20, 1952 (Folder 13)
  - "The Strange Case of the I.P.R.," American Legion Magazine, Mar. 1952 (Folder 14)
  - Review of William Hillman, Mr. President, and Chester Wilmot, The Struggle for Europe, Economic Council Review of Books, Apr. 1952 (Folder 15)
  - "The Isolationism of 'Internationalists,'" Commonweal, Apr. 11, 1952 (Folder 16)
  - "The China Lobby," Reporter, May 27, 1952 (letter to the editor) (Folder 17)
  - "Die Bedeutung der Amerikanischen Praesidentschaftswahlen fuer Deutschland," June 17, 1952 (speech, Deutsche Parlamentarische Gesellschaft, Bonn) (Folder 18)
  - "Germany's Fifth Man," Pathfinder, Oct. 22, 1952 (Folder 19)
  - "Facing Both Ways in Germany," Freeman, Dec. 15, 1952 (Folder 20)
  - "The Saar: A 'Free' Police State," Human Events, Dec. 31, 1952 (Folder 21)
  - "Shall Freedom Ring?" 1953 (Folder 22)
  - "Atlantic Disunion," Human Events, Feb. 25, 1953 (Folder 23)
  - "Germany's Dilemma," Freeman, Mar. 9, 1953 (Folder 24)
  - Testimony, U.S. Senate Committee on Government Operations Permanent Subcommittee on Investigations, Apr. 1, 1953 (Folder 25)
  - Letter to the editor, Washington Times-Herald, Apr. 3, 1953 (date written) (Folder 26)
  - "Report from Washington," Apr. 13, 1953 (Folder 27)
  - "Timely Reappraisal," Freeman, May 4, 1953 (review of Norbert Muhlen, The Return of Germany) (Folder 28)
  - "Facing the Facts in Germany," American Mercury, June 1953 (Folder 29)
  - "Appeasement 'la Mode,'" Human Events, June 24, 1953 (Folder 30)
  - "France and Germany," July 10, 1953 (Folder 31)
  - "Theory versus Fact," Freeman, July 27, 1953 (review of Arnold J. Toynbee, The World and the West) (Folder 32)
  - "Second Chance in Germany," American Legion Magazine, Oct. 1953 (Folder 33)
  - "Freda Utley's Answer to Criticism of Her Article 'Second Chance in Germany,'" Nov. 19, 1953 (Folder 34)
  - "The Book Burners Burned," American Mercury, Dec. 1953 (Folder 35)
  - "Victor's Justice: Then and Now," Dec. 8, 1953 (Folder 36)
  - "War Crimes Trials and American Security," Dec. 9, 1953 (Folder 37)
  - "The Spectre of Rapallo," 1954 (Folder 38)
  - "England after Austerity," Freeman, Feb. 22, 1954 (Box 26., Folder 1)
  - "Lion into Ostrich," Freeman, Mar. 8, 1954 (Folder 2)
  - "Berlin: The Republican Yalta?" Human Events, Mar. 10, 1954 (Folder 3)
  - "A Plan for Molotov," Freeman, Apr. 19, 1954 (Folder 4)
  - Testimony, U.S. Senate Committee on the Judiciary Subcommittee to Investigate the Administration of the Internal Security Act and Other Internal Security Laws, July 1, 1954 (Folder 5)
  - "Scribes and Pharisees," Human Events, July 28, 1954 (Folder 6)
  - "France against Europe," Sept. 13, 1954 (Folder 7)
  - "Kremlin Orchestra," Freeman, Oct. 1954 (review of Joseph Z. Kornfeder, Brainwashing and Senator McCarthy) (Folder 8)
  - "That London Agreement," Human Events, Oct. 20, 1954 (Folder 9)
  - "Malmedy and McCarthy," American Mercury, Nov. 1954 (Folder 10)
  - Untitled, 1955 (Folder 11)
  - "Was It Planned that Way?" Human Events, Jan. 1, 1955 (Folder 12)
  - "Russians Hate Communists," Facts Forum News, Feb. 1955 (Folder 13)
  - "A Program to Govern Our Foreign Relations," New York Times, Feb. 28, 1955 (paid political advertisement; co-signer with others) (Folder 14)
  - "Modern Barbarism," Freeman, Mar. 1955 (review of Whitney R. Harris, Tyranny on Trial: The Evidence at Nuremberg, F. J. P. Veale, Advance to Barbarism, and K. O. Kurth, comp., Documents of Humanity) (Folder 15)
  - "Peace in Our Time?" Facts Forum News, Apr. 1955 (Folder 16)
  - "Yalta Then and Now," Human Events, Apr. 16, 1955 (Folder 17)
  - Speech, Apr. 25, 1955 (Folder 18)
  - Letter to the editor, Washington Post, May 12, 1955 (date written) (Folder 19)
  - "The Truce of the Bear: Present Communist Strategy," Human Events, May 21, 1955 (Folder 20)
  - "The Triumph of Owen Lattimore," American Mercury, June 1955 (Folder 21)
  - "Geneva - and a New Pattern of Soviet Imperialism," Human Events, July 16, 1955 (Folder 22)
  - "Can We Be Sure of Germany?" Facts Forum News, Oct. 1955 (Folder 23)
  - "Can the Kremlin Relax?" Nov. 15, 1955 (speech) (Folder 24)
  - "The World Views the U.S.," National Review, Nov. 26, 1955 (column) (Folder 25)
  - "The German Cycle," Freeman, Dec. 1955 (review of Ernst von Salomon, The Questionnaire [Fragebogen]) (Folder 26)
  - "The World Views the U.S.: British Comments on American Politics," National Review, Dec. 28, 1955 (column) (Folder 27)
  - "End of the Adenauer Era?" 1956 (Folder 28)
  - "The Formosa Story," 1956 (Folder 29)
  - "Formosan Surprises," 1956 (Folder 30)
  - "Friends, Enemies and Neutrals: From Formosa to Cairo in 1956," 1956 (Folder 31)
  - "The Hong Kong Mind," 1956 (Folder 32)
  - "'No Flies on Formosa,'" 1956 (Folder 33)
  - "On the Island of Formosa," 1956 (Folder 34)
  - "With the Free Chinese Armed Forces," 1956 (Folder 35)
  - "The World Views the U.S.," Jan. 9, 1956 (column; date written) (Folder 36)
  - "India: Neutral against Whom?" Human Events, Jan. 28, 1956 (Folder 37)
  - "Chinese Red and Scholastic Blue," National Review, Feb. 1, 1956 (review of Richard L. Walker, China under Communism, and James Cameron, Mandarin Red) (Folder 38)
  - "The World Views the U.S.: Mr. Dulles' Best Defense - from England," National Review, Feb. 15, 1956 (column) (Folder 39)
  - "Living Letters from the Dead," National Review, Feb. 29, 1956 (review of Last Letters from Stalingrad) (Folder 40)
  - "The World Views the U.S.," National Review, Mar. 14, 1956 (column) (Folder 41)
  - "The World Views the U.S.," National Review, Mar. 28, 1956 (column) (Folder 42)
  - "Escape," National Review, June 13, 1956 (review of Markoosha Fischer, The Right to Love) (Folder 43)
  - "Hong Kong in Mid-1956," June 27, 1956 (Folder 44)
  - "No Softening of U.S. Policy, Nixon's Reassurance," Cincinnati Enquirer, July 20, 1956 (Folder 45)
  - "No Escape from Fate," National Review, Aug. 1, 1956 (review of Luigi Villari, Italian Foreign Policy under Mussolini) (Folder 46)
  - Untitled, Sept. 4, 1956 (Folder 47)
  - "Formosa Is Striving to Set an Example for All of Asia," Sunday Tiger Standard (Hong Kong), Sept. 9, 1956 (Folder 48)
  - "The Voice of China as Heard in Hong Kong," Sept. 12, 1956 (Folder 49)
  - "'Old-Hat' Notions of Marxism 'Modern' in Tokyo: The Strange Case of Japan," Standard-Times (New Bedford, Mass.), Sept. 25, 1956 (Folder 50)
  - "The Amazing Mr. Diem," National Review, Nov. 24, 1956 (Folder 51)
  - "Taiwan: Trial and Error," National Review, Dec. 22, 1956 (Folder 52)
  - Will the Middle East Go West? 1957
    - Drafts (Box 27., Folder 1-2)
    - Printed copy (Folder 3)
    - Promotional material (Folder 4)
    - Reviews (Folder 5)
  - "Letter from Formosa: A Going Concern," National Review, Jan. 26, 1957 (Folder 6)
  - "Dissent on Egypt," National Review, Mar. 9, 1957 (Folder 7)
  - "Nationalizing Suez: Legality of Egyptian Move Said to Be Supported by Record," New York Times, Mar. 12, 1957 (letter to the editor) (Folder 8)